And welcome to the next part of visualizing the data.
데이터 시각화의 다음 단계에 오신 걸 환영해요
And just very quickly to show it to you in 3D.
재빨리 3D로 보여드릴 수 있죠
My box managed to survive me restarting and getting rid of that massive plot.
그 거대한 부지를 없애고 다시 켜고 나서도 제 상자는 무사했어요
I hope you didn't follow my track, but you did it more sensibly.
제 방식을 따라 하지 않으셨길 바라요 하지만 더 현명하게 선택하셨네요
Anyways, now to visualize in 3D just again, to get that that sense of appreciation for what it means
어쨌든 3D로 시각화해 보겠습니다 텍스트의 벡터 삽입이 어떤 의미인지 이해하기
to have a vector embedding of text.
위해서요 get it
This time I have stuck with a more reasonable 10,000, boringly and otherwise.
이번에는 좀 더 합리적인 10,000를 택했어요 지루하고 특이하죠
The code is just like we did it before when we looked at Rag, and we create the scatter plot using
코드는 전에 Rag에서 했던 것과 같아요 Plotly 라이브러리를 이용해 다시 산란
the Plotly library again.
플롯을 생성하죠
And this is what it looks like in the 3D visualization.
3D 시각화로 보면 이런 모습이에요
It's hard to stop it from from zooming in and out, but there we go.
줌인과 아웃을 막기는 어렵지만 어쨌든 됐네요
And just as before, when we looked at the much smaller vector data space, it looks a little bit,
전에 비트를 봤을 때처럼 훨씬 작은 벡터 데이터 공간을 보면
um, uh, strange from, from a distance like that.
이렇게 멀리서 보면 좀 이상해 보여요
But when you rotate it around and you interact with it, You absolutely start to see you get to appreciate
하지만 회전시키고 상호 작용해보면 3D의 진가를 확실히 알게 될 겁니다 관련 제품을
the 3D, and you get to see how there are clusters that represent related kinds of products.
나타내는 클러스터가 어떻게 있는지 말이에요 Get in get get it
And you can actually copy the code that we used before.
전에 사용한 코드를 복사할 수 있어요
So you get it to print the text of each one if you wish.
원한다면 각각의 텍스트를 get으로 출력할 수 있어요.
It will use up more memory again, but you can do that.
메모리를 더 쓰게 될 텐데 그래도 괜찮아요
And that's a pretty cool way to satisfy yourself that the data is being represented in this way, that
데이터는 비슷한 것들이 서로 가깝게 표현된다는 점에서 스스로 만족할 수
similar things are close to each other.
있는 멋진 방법이죠
That's really the important takeaway here.
그게 정말 중요한 부분이죠
And you'll see when when purple dots have strayed away from the mainstream, you'll you'll get a sense
그리고 보라색 점이 주류에서 벗어난 이유를 알게 될 거예요 Get
of why.
it
And it's really helpful to do that.
그게 정말 도움이 돼요
So this is again more more of an exercise to build intuition designed to help see that as we scale up
이건 직관을 키우기 위한 연습에 가까워요 훨씬 많은 문서에 대한 래그의 규모를 키워도
rag to this much bigger problem with much larger number of documents, that the same rules apply, and
같은 규칙이 적용되고 데이터를 시각화하고 실험할 수
that you can visualize and experiment with your data in much the same way.
있다는 걸 보여주기 위해서요
Quite enough preamble on on vector data stores.
벡터 데이터 저장소 얘기는 충분히 들었어요
It's time for us to actually build the Rag pipeline to estimate product prices using similar products.
이제 래그 파이프라인을 구축해서 비슷한 제품을 이용해 제품 가격을 추정할 때예요
Let's get to it.
Get it, get it 해 보죠